gainhigherground.com 2013-05-15

# Privacy Policy

As a visitor to Gain Higher Ground want to know that your privacy is important to us.

This page of the website outlines what type of personal information we receive and store when you visit our site. It also covers how we use and safeguard this information. We will never sell or distribute your personal information to third parties.

**Log Files**  
As is the case with most other internet sites, we store and use the information contained within log files.  This information includes your internet protocol (IP) address, your internet service provider (ISP), the type of browser you used to visit GainHigherGround.Com (E.g., Google Chrome, Firefox or Microsoft Internet Explorer), the date and time you visited our site and the selection of pages you visited whilst here.

**Cookies and Web Beacons**  
This site uses cookies to store information. For example, your personal preferences are recorded when you visit GainHigherGround.Com. This information is useful for such things as only showing you a popup once in your visit, or to facilitate your ability to view some of this site’s pages, such as forums.

In addition, we use employ third party advertisements on GainHigherGround.Com  to provide financial support for our site. These advertisers use web technology such as web beacons and cookies when they advertise on our site. These items will send these advertisers (e.g., Google via the Google AdSense program) information including your ISP, your IP address and the type of browser you use. In some cases, whether you have Flash installed. This is primarily used for geotargeting purposes. For example, if you are based in Los Angeles then it could be used to display advertisements relating to Real Estate agents located in that area. Alternatively, it could be used to display certain ads based on specific sites you have visited. For example, you might see more adverts relating to gardening products if you frequent gardening sites regularly.

**DoubleClick DART cookies**  
We also may use DART cookies for ad serving through Google’s DoubleClick. This technology places a cookie on your computer when you are browsing the web and visit a site using DoubleClick advertising (including some Google AdSense advertisements). This cookie is used to serve ads specific to you and your interests. This is known as “interest based targeting” and is aimed at enhancing your web browsing experience. Your previous browsing history will be used to help determine which ads you will be shown. For example, if you have been viewing sites about visiting New York, you might see New York hotel advertisements when visiting a non-related site, such as on a site about cooking). DART uses “non personally identifiable information” and it does NOT track personal information about you, such as your name, email address, physical address, telephone number, social security numbers, bank account numbers or credit card numbers. If you wish you can opt-out of this ad serving on all sites using this advertising by visiting <http://www.google.com/privacy/ads/>. Alternatively you may opt-out of a third party vendor’s use of cookies by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page which can be found [here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

Finally, you can, if you wish, choose to disable or selectively turn off our cookies or third-party cookies in your browser settings, or by managing preferences in programs such as Norton Internet Security. However, this is likely to affect how you are able to interact with this site as well as other websites. This could include the inability to login to services or programs, such as logging into forums or accounts.

It is important to note that deleting cookies does not mean you are permanently opted out of any advertising program. Unless you have settings that disallow cookies, the next time you visit a site running the advertisements, a new cookie will be added.

**Comment Policy**

Comments are welcomed and encouraged on this site, but there are some instances where comments will be edited or deleted as follows:

1\. Comments deemed to be spam or questionable spam will be deleted. Including a link to relevant content is permitted, but comments should be relevant to the post topic.

2\. Comments including profanity will be deleted.

3\. Comments containing language or concepts that could be deemed offensive will be deleted.

4\. Comments that attack a person individually will be deleted.

The owner of this blog reserves the right to edit or delete any comments submitted to this blog without notice. This comment policy is subject to change at any time.

**Finally**

If you have any questions regarding any of this information then please get in touch via the Contact Us section of this site. Alternatively, you may email us at rob [at] gainhigherground.com
